Joseph Osho

lagos, Lagos State • +2349134248820 • oshojoseph2@gmail.com • <u>linkedin.com/in/joseph-osho-627211235</u> • www.twitter.com/graph_art_lawd • <u>https://oshojoseph.onrender.com/</u>

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

5+ years of full-stack development experience in full-stack web and mobile applications with an emphasis on performance & security with Proven ability to collaborate with UX/UI designers and product managers to deliver solutions aligning with business goals and leading teams of developers in creating visually appealing and functional web and mobile applications to be Deployed on multiple hosting platforms and stores.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lordwin Group • lagos • Full-time • 11/2023 - Present

Tech developer of online games and bets

Frontend Developer

• Successfully developed a mobile application with five distinct theme modes, providing users with a diverse and personalized visual experience.

Impact Apps • lagos • Part-time • 11/2023 - 01/2024

Tech application developing company

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

- Successfully implemented a cross-platform mobile application using React Native, showcasing versatility in iOS and Android development.
- Orchestrated the backend using Node.js, demonstrating proficiency in server-side JavaScript development.
- Integrated MongoDB to handle data storage and management efficiently, ensuring optimal performance and scalability.
- Implemented OAuth2 for secure and seamless user authentication for social accounts(twitter, Instagram,tiktok), prioritizing user privacy and data protection.
- Utilized Socket.IO to establish real-time communication, enabling dynamic updates and live interactions within the application.
- Demonstrated expertise in iOS development using Xcode, ensuring a polished and native-like user experience on Apple devices

Robosys Labs

Lead Frontend Developer

- Developed fully responsive landing page and waitlist submit form with validation for the Maeedits Platform app (https://maeedits.com)
- Developed fully responsive landing page and waitlist submit form with validation for the Bammby dating app (https://bammby.com)
- Modifying the Remedy Portal website and added a visually appealing CV page for resume rebrands (https://cv.remedyportal.com)
- Designed and developed The Hair-market e-commerce website using React framework https://hairmarket.ng
- Implemented mobile app features such as push notifications, Biometric and Google authentication, universal deep linking for Remedy app

- Conducted testing of beta app releases on both Android and IOS platforms, focusing on features and functionality
- Published compiled test and final build release version of application to both Android and IOS platforms
- Presented PRs for features done in the web and mobile applications for reviews and merge
- · Integrated backend APIs with frontend for consumption and rendering of data
- Ensured seamless usage of data on the web browser by optimizing web page loading speed, reducing latency and improving data caching mechanisms
- Constructed a backup full stack web application for the Remedy CV page during server downtime
- Updated & modularised old code bases to modern development standards as part of slashing operational costs

Digibrand • lagos • Full-time • 01/2020 - 06/2022

A web application development provider service

Fullstack Developer

- Developed and deployed full-stack functional web applications for data processing, analysis, and visualization
- · Spearheaded the creation of responsive and functional web applications
- Applied strategies to facilitate effective communication among team members, resulting in 25% increase productivity and team morale
- · Setting up and deploying web applications on hosting platforms like Heroku and AWS
- Managed timely updates to web applications, including content changes and database upgrades
- Created a real-time chat web application using Socket.io as a transport connection and Node.js as the backend
- Facilitated web3 wallet connection authentication to secure Ethereum Blockchain transactions
- Initiated an email notification system to keep users informed about website updates and news

EDUCATION

Higher National Diploma

Moshood Abiola Polytechnic • Abeokuta, Ogun, Nigeria • 11/2014 - 01/2020

Cloud Development • 09/2022 - 11/2022

End Web Development

University Of Science And Technology • 10/2021 - 12/2021

CERTIFICATIONS

Frontend Development with React

University of Science and Technology Hong Kong • 10/2021 - 12/2021

Cloud Development With AWS

UDACITY/ALX • 08/2022 - 11/2022

Hairmarket.ng

Robosys Labs • 11/2022 - 04/2023

https://hairmarket.ng

Remedy Cv

Robosys Labs • 06/2023 - 07/2023

https://cv.remedyportal.com

Ayojagun

Private Videographer • 05/2023 - 06/2023

Portfolio Website for Videographer /Cinematographer

https://ayojagun.com

Remedy Portal

Robosys Labs • 06/2023 - 12/2023

https://remedyportal.com

Remedy Mobile

Robosys Labs • 06/2023 - 08/2023

Remedy mobile App on Google Play Store and App store

Bammby

Robosys Labs • 09/2023 - 09/2023

Responsive Landing Page and waitlist submit page for the Bammby Dating App

Maeedits Landing/Waitlist

Maeedits • 09/2023 - 09/2023

Dice.ng

Lordwin games

www.dice.ng

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Amazon Web Services, App publishing, Bootstrap, Cascading Style Sheet, Cloud Development, Computer Graphics, DynamoDB, Firebase, Front End Web Development, Git, Hypertext Markup Language, JavaScript, Jira, Mobile Application Development, MongoDB, Monorepo, Next Js, Node.JS, NoSQL, Nx, PostgreSQL, ReactJS, React Native, React Native, Redux, Representational State Transfer, Socket.IO, Software Engineering, SQL, Tailwind CSS, Trello, Typescript, vue js, Web Application, Web Development, Zustand, Reading, Socializing